I have been a fool.
我真傻 真的
Made mistakes. Monumental ones.
我犯过错误 大错特错
I now realize that I was never destined to be  a leader,
现在我明白了 我永远都不会成为一名领袖
or even an equal partner.
更不用说和他平起平坐
And, I'm at peace with that.
不过 我现在已经尘埃落定
I have gained a clear understanding of my place in this universe,
我已经认清了自己在宇宙中的位置
of who I am, of who I was always meant to be.
认清了自我 那个自始至终的我
Starscream, second-in-command,
红蜘蛛 副指挥官
humble servant to Lord Megatron.
威震天陛下的心腹侍从
Thank you for listening, Soundwave.
谢谢你的聆听 声波
Is this true?
这是真的吗？
Starscream never mentioned it?
红蜘蛛从没说起过吗？
If he's up to his old tricks,
如果他又想故技重施
I shall grind him into powder.
我一定把他捏成碎屑
Starscream?
红蜘蛛？
Lord Megatron, please excuse Airachnid's impertinence.
威震天陛下 请原谅毒蜘蛛的无礼取闹
Now, what was it that I allegedly failed to mention?
好了 我忘了告诉您什么鬼东西吗？
The Harbinger.
先驱号
What about it?
怎么了?
Eons ago a Decepticon transport crash-landed on this planet.
许多年前 一艘霸天虎运输船在这个星球坠毁
Oh, please, common knowledge.
噢 拜托 这谁都知道
I scouted the crash site when we first arrived on Earth.
刚到地球时 我就去查看了坠机地点
Then I presume you recovered the experimental weapon prototype the Harbinger had been transporting?
那么我猜 你一定已经收回了 先驱号运载的武器原型吧？
Where is the crash site?
坠机地点在哪儿？
It was never logged into your ship's database.
地点并没有录入飞船的数据库
You failed to record the coordinates of a Decepticon transport?
你没有记录霸天虎运输船的坐标？
An oversight, master.
是我疏忽 主人
But I noted its exact location.
但确切位置就在我脑子里
Then you can lead Airachnid there.
那你就带毒蜘蛛过去
So that she may retrieve the prototype for me.
让她把那件武器原型给我带回来
My personal native guide.
我有私人本地导游了
How delightful.
真高兴
Hey, partner,
嘿 搭档
heck of a view you got up here.
你这里风景不错嘛
If there's even a small chance your spark is out there listening, well...
但愿你的火种还能听到我说话 其实…
we could really use you, Cliff.
我们真的需要你 小飞
Seems like every day another Decepticon arrives on the scene.
最近几乎每天都有新的霸天虎冒出来
We are outnumbered and outgunned.
我们人手不够 火力不足
Yea, I know what you'd say.
算了 我知道你会说
'Sounds like a fair fight.'
“看来要好好打一仗了”
And if that's the world we live in, so be it.
如果我们注定生活在这样的世界 那无所谓
I just want you to know:
我只想让你知道
I haven't given up.
我没有放弃
I'm going to find the Con who took you from us.
我要把杀死你的虎子揪出来
Your chosen vehicle mode lacks thrust.
你的机械形态缺乏冲刺的快感
Are you going to preen or are you going to guide?
你是来领路的 还是来显摆的？
I will reveal the exact location of the Harbinger,
我会告诉你先驱号的准确位置
when you tell me exactly what we are looking for.
可你得说清楚 我们在找什么
That information is need-to-know.
到时候自然真相大白
And right now, you don't.
现在嘛 你不必知道
Oh, You would do well to respect me, Airachnid.
噢 你最好放尊重一点 毒蜘蛛
Before I joined Megatron,
在投靠威震天之前
I was Air Commander of a squadron of Energon Seekers.
我可是能量追踪者中队的空军指挥官
On Cybertron, and how many eons ago was that?
那是在塞博特恩 离现在有些年头了吧？
Just recently,
就在最近
I personally vanquished one of Optimus Prime's fiercest warriors--Cliff Jumper.
我一个人干掉了擎天柱的得力干将之一 飞过山
You snuffed an Autobot?
你干掉了一个汽车人？
Yes I did. Without mercy.
是的 没错 丝毫没有手软
Oh, even Megatron showed you mercy when he planned to terminate you at the mine.
噢 威震天本想在矿井里把你干掉 可他也一时心软
What? He told you about that?
什么？他连这都告诉你了？
We talk.
聊天而已
The wreckage lies just beneath where we stand.
飞船残骸就在我们所在位置的正下方
I will need to find a point of entry.
我得去找个入口
Show off.
真能显摆
Suit yourself, I conducted a thorough search of this husk years ago.
随便你吧 多年前我就已经把这里翻遍了
What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
Accessing the cargo manifest,
访问货物清单
or didn't you think to do that during your thorough search?
你在翻遍这里的时候 没想过这么做吗？
Idiot. The ship's systems haven't been activated for eons.
笨蛋 飞船的系统几个世纪以来都没有激活
The Autobots could detect its energy signature.
汽车人会探测到它的能量特征
Ah, here it is. Section 23.
啊 找到了 在23区
Optimus, our scanners have detected a Decepticon energy profile,
擎天柱 我们侦测到一个霸天虎的能量特征
but it's... ancient.
但是种…古老的信号
The past has a way of catching up with the present, Ratchet.
历史总是可以和当代接轨 救护车
Section 23 should be right about... here.
23区应该就在…这儿
The ship just ends.
飞船到头了
It must have broken in half during the crash.
它一定是在坠落时断成了两截
Or in the air.
也许在空中已经断了
If you performed actual research,
如果你真的做过研究
You would have learned that an Autobot battalion shot the Harbinger out of the sky.
不会不知道 先驱号是被汽车人部队从天上打下来的
How far away is the other half?
另一半飞船离这儿多远？
I'm afraid that information is needed-to-know.
应该说 到时候自然真相大白
What are you...
你要…
You're trying to make me look like a fool before Megatron.
你想让我在威震天面前出丑吗？
Have me return empty handed while you locate that weapon yourself.
让我空手而归 而你去独吞那个武器
How dare you acuse me!
你竟敢指责我！
You are nothing but a scavenger, an opportunist.
你不过是个食腐动物 喜欢投机取巧！
Aren't you one to talk?
你不也是这种人吗？
Perhaps, but I've changed,
也许吧 但我已经洗心革面了
seeing the error of my ways.
从前我曾经走错过路
I live to serve Megatron now.
但我现在活着的目的 就为威震天效劳
You won't live to serve anyone if you don't tell me where to find the rest of the ship, now.
你休想活命 除非你告诉我另一半飞船在哪儿 快说！
A few kliks north of here through a stone arch.
向北走几公里 穿过一道石拱门
Now release me!
快把我放开！
When I have the weapon in hand.
我拿到武器后 就放了你
That is, if I can find my way back without my guide.
不过 但愿在没人带路的情况下 我能找回来
This is not funny, Airachnid,
这可不好玩儿 毒蜘蛛
come back here right now and cut me lose.
马上回来给我松绑
Airachnid, that is an order!
毒蜘蛛 这是命令！
I am your commanding officer!
我是你的指挥官！
Airachnid.
毒蜘蛛
Surrender.
投降吧
Airachnid, you traitor!
毒蜘蛛 你这个叛徒！
Arcee, wait!
阿尔茜 等等！
Arcee.
阿尔茜
I didn't peg you for resigning with the Decepticons.
我没想到 你会重新投奔霸天虎
A temporary arrangement, Arcee.
缓兵之计罢了 阿尔茜
You know I prefer working alone.
你知道 我更喜欢单干
Speaking of add anymore deceased partners to your growing list?
话说 想在成长日志里 再加上几个阵亡战友的名字吗？
Airachnid, release her.
毒蜘蛛 放开她
Arcee, you know better than to engage the enemy alone.
阿尔茜 你应该知道 不能独自和敌人交战
Not her. Not after what she did to Tailgate.
她是例外 她把挡板害惨了
No, please. Tailgate!
不 求你了 挡板！
She will pay.
她必须付出代价
Revenge will not bring back those we have lost.
复仇并不能让牺牲的战士回来
Is that understood?
明白吗？
Move it.
快走
No need to use force.
用不着动粗吧
I'll tell you anything you want to know.
你们想知道什么 我全说
Hehe, is that right?
呵呵 真的吗？
And what you want in return?
你想要什么回报？
I want to be on your side.
我想要…加入你们
On our side? Haha, yeah, right.
加入我们？哈哈 你要是能当汽车人
And I've been lobbing with the Fallen!
我还能跟堕落金刚玩抛球呢！
You wouldn't betray the Decepticons.
你不会背叛霸天虎的
Wouldn't I?
为什么不会？
What have they done for me lately,
他们最近都是怎么待我的
besides humiliate me,
除了羞辱我
spy on me, demote me?
监视我 还降我的级
Megatron tried to extinguish my spark in cold blood,
威震天不念旧情 想把我干掉
then all but to replace me with that treacherous wretch Airachnid.
还有那个一心想取代我的混蛋毒蜘蛛
She abandoned me!
她竟然丢下我不管！
Left me for scrap!
让我自生自灭！
So why not rat them out?
所以 干嘛不过河拆桥呢？
He is telling the truth about Megatron trying to scrap him.
他说的是实话 威震天的确想杀了他
I saw with my own eyes.
是我亲眼看见的
You're not saying you actually trust Starscream?
你不是想说 你相信红蜘蛛吧？
Trust him? Never.
相信他？绝不会
But this may be the one time our objective's alined.
但这次我们也许能联手对敌
You're right to be wary, Bulkhead.
你的担心很有道理 隔板
But I agree with Arcee.
但我赞成阿尔茜
Be still, my beating spark.
我简直按捺不住火种的狂跳
What do you know.
你猜怎么着
Could still be a trap.
可能又是个陷阱
Starscream's loyalty to Megatron has always been questionable.
红蜘蛛在威震天面前一直三心二意
If he has truly split from the Decepticons,
如果他真的和霸天虎决裂
our prisoner's knowledge of their agendas could make him a valuable ally.
这个了解军情的俘虏 也许是个值得结交的盟友
You don't mean permanently?
你不是认真的吧？
As in key to the base and everything?
难道要把基地的钥匙也交给他吗？
However unlikely that scenario,
尽管有些不切实际
every sentient being deserves an opportunity for redemption.
但每个生命体都应该得到赎罪的机会
Even Bot-killers? Even Airachnid?
即使他是汽车人杀手吗？那毒蜘蛛呢？
Without that hope, we may never achieve lasting peace.
如果不抱这个希望 我们可能永远得不到长治久安
Rise and shine, Screamy.
太阳晒屁股了 蜘蛛侠
We are here. Where is the ship?
我们到了 飞船在哪里？
It's through the arch, among the stones.
穿过石拱门 在石堆中间
Bulkhead, Bumblebee, you are with me.
隔板 大黄蜂 跟我来
Arcee, remain with our prisoner.
阿尔茜 留下看管战俘
Optimus, please.
擎天柱 求你了
For Tailgate.
为了挡板
Your desire to avenge Tailgate will only continue to cloud your judgement.
你渴望为挡板复仇 只会一再影响你的判断力
Is the clamp really necessary?
真的有必要用手铐吗？
I promise not to fly away.
我保证不飞走
It's really giving me a crick.
我都要抽筋了
I can shove you back in the trailer.
我把你扔回车箱里如何
Be alert.
保持警惕
Airachnid is known to attack from below ground.
毒蜘蛛善于从地下攻击
Right.
明白
I got it.
让我来
The Immobilizer. True to its name.
静止器 果然名不虚传
I'm not really so bad, you know.
我并没有那么坏 你知道
Megatron, he is the evil one.
威震天才是十恶不赦的坏人
Tell it to someone who cares.
跟那些想听的人说去吧
Like whom? Airachnid?
跟谁说？毒蜘蛛？
What I wouldn't do to get my hands around her wretched throat.
我无时无刻不想掐住她该死的脖子
So we can agree on one thing.
这一点 我们倒可以达成一致
Oh, you have no idea.
噢 你根本想不到
She showed up one day,
她莫名其妙地出现
and the next thing you know, she is acting like she runs the place.
然后呢 她就像个大管家一样
She whispered lies into Megatron's ear,
她对威震天吹枕边风
maneuvered to rob me of my rightful place.
而且还坐上了本座的交椅！
Well, she terminated my partner.
是啊 她还杀了我的搭档
What?! She is taking credit for scrapping him now, too?!
什么？！她把杀掉他的功劳安在自己头上？！
That was my doing!
那是我干的！
What?
什么？
You weren't there.
你当时不在场
Ah, of course I wasn't.
啊 我当然不在
I don't know what I was thinking.
我不知道刚才在想什么
Who are you talking about?
你说的是谁？
No one, who are you talking about?
谁也没说 你说的是谁？
Tailgate.
挡板
Who's Tailgate?
谁是挡板？
You were the one.
原来是你
You extinguished Cliffjumper.
是你杀了飞过山
Cliffjumper?
飞过山？
No, no, no, no.
不 不 不
You misunderstand.
你搞错了
It wasn't like you think.
不是你想的那样
The Troopers mortally wounded him.
机械兵打得他半死不活
I was trying to help Cliffjumper...
我是想帮助飞过山…
put him out of his misery.
帮他结束痛苦
He begged me to!
是他求我的！
OK, OK! it was a mistake!
好吧 好吧！这是个失误！
I've made many, but I've changed!
我曾经犯过错误 但我已经改了！
You wouldn't terminate a defenceless prisoner, would you?
你不会杀害一个手无寸铁的俘虏 对吧？
What... what is that?
什么…那是什么？
The key to your cuffs.
你手铐的钥匙
What for?
为什么？
Cliff would have given you a fighting chance.
换成小飞 他会给你一个决斗的机会
No. Please, I... I don't want to!
不 求你 我不想决斗！
What's past is past.
过去的都过去了
I'm one of you now!
现在我是你们的一员！
No, no, no, no...
不 不 不…
Take it!
把它捡起来！
You're pathetic.
胆小鬼
Something wrong, Arcee?
有问题吗 阿尔茜？
I thought you wanted a fight.
我还以为你想决斗呢
Freeze.
不许动
You are tougher to scrap than your former partner,
你比你的前搭档棘手一点
at least the one I scrapped.
至少比我杀掉的那个强
Was Tailgate weak like Cliffjumper?
挡板也像飞过山一样不堪一击吗？
Just keep talking, Starscream.
有种就接着说 红蜘蛛
Tell me, bug.
告诉我 虫子
Do you think Megatron will enjoy his new trophies?
你认为 威震天会喜欢他的新战利品吗？
He'll probably use the bulky one here for target practice.
他也许会用这个大块头来当靶子
Prime is the true prize.
擎天柱啊 真是物有所值
Perhaps he'll adorn the prow of Megatron's warship.
也许可以用他来装饰威震天战舰的船首
But you, bug.
至于你 虫子
I suspect Meagtron will simply dismantle you for spare parts.
我怀疑 威震天只会把你当废铁拆掉
As a rogue, a scavenger,
作为一个游侠 一只食腐动物
I should disappear into the night with this treasure.
我应该带着这个宝贝消失在夜色里
But using it to warm my way into Megatron's favor is too good an opportunity to pass up.
但是 用它来取悦威震天 是个不容错过的大好机会
Wouldn't you say, Prime?
你说是不是 擎天柱？
I mean with results like this.
有了这样的战绩
I could earn Megatron's eternal trust.
我可以成为威震天的心腹
You fool!
你这个白痴！
You should have finished me when I was hopeless to fight.
你应该趁我不能还手的时候杀了我
Just like I finished Cliffjumper.
就像我杀死飞过山一样
Now, prepare to reunite with your partners.
现在 准备和你的那些搭档团聚吧
What's that? I can't hear your last words.
说什么？我听不见你的遗言
This is for Cliffjumper!
这…是…为了…飞过山！
Go on. Do it!
来吧 动手吧！
Megatron will only terminate me for treason if I dare return to the Decepticons.
如果回到霸天虎那里 威震天只会当我谋反 把我杀掉
You may as well be the one to put me out of my misery.
你可以成为那个 帮我结束痛苦的人
As if I needed convincing.
你以为我需要怂恿吗？
What? Wait! No!
什么？等等！不！
You left Starscream with the Autobots?!
你让红蜘蛛落在汽车人手里？！
Do you have any notion of the consequences of your blunder?!
你知不知道 你的愚蠢失误会带来什么后果？！
But, my lordship!
但是 阁下！
It was Starscream's incompetence that cost us the Immobilizer!
丢掉了静止器 全怪红蜘蛛无能！
I don't care about some trinket!
我才不在乎那个小玩意儿！
My second-in-command is a prisoner of the enemy!
我的副官成了敌人的阶下囚！
Which means all Decepticon intelligence could be at the fingertips of the Autobots!
这就是说 霸天虎的所有情报 可能已经落入了汽车人的手里！
The damage look bad,
破损情况很严重
but it was a snap to repair,
但很容易就修好了
allowing us to reverse its effect on you.
可以把对你们的效用逆转
You should regain your full range of motion before long.
你们应该很快就能行动自如了
And Arcee?
那阿尔茜呢？
She is rather resilient for a two-wheeler.
作为一辆两轮车 她恢复得够快了
It is the external wounds which heal the quickest.
痊愈的只是那些皮外伤
I thought settling scores would allow me to move on...
我以为 拼命杀敌会让我忘掉过去
Instead, I chased away our hope of winning this war anytime soon.
但是 我却把早日结束战争的希望赶跑了
Wisdom cannot be granted, Arcee.
智慧并不是天生的 阿尔茜
It must be earned, sometimes at a cost.
必须靠拼搏得来 有时要付出代价
I have been a fool.
我真傻 真的
Made mistakes.
我犯过错误
Monumental ones.
大错特错
But I have gained a clear understanding of my place in this universe.
但是 我已经认清了自己在宇宙中的位置
Of who I am.
认清了自我
Starscream: aligned with no side,
红蜘蛛
servant, to no one.
不效忠任何人